《越狱》第四季 第一集
Prison.Break.S04E01
《越狱》第四季 第二集
Prison.Break.S04EE02
我叫迈克尔・斯科菲尔德  我是一名逃犯
My name is Michael Scofield, I am a fugitive.
三周前  我被关在巴拿马的一所监狱里
Three weeks ago, I was incarcerated In a Panamanian prison.
在那里...
While I was there...
公司找到了我
I was approached by the Company...
公司是一个腐败堕落的...
The company is a corrupt organization...
渗透到行业和政府中各个层面的组织
Involved in all levels of industry and government.
他们给了我两个选择
They gave me two options.
帮助他们的人詹姆斯・惠斯勒越狱
Break one of their men. James Whistler out of that prison.
否则就杀了我最爱的女人
Or they would kill the only woman I ever loved.
莎拉・唐克雷蒂医生
Dr. Sara Tancredi.
我遵守了承诺  帮助惠斯勒成功越狱
I held up my end of deal and I broke Whistler out.
但公司...
But the Company...
还是杀了莎拉
They killed Sara anyway.
我不知为何公司要詹姆斯・惠斯勒越狱
I don't know why the Company wanted James Whistler out of prison.
但我跟踪他来到了洛杉矶
But I've tracked him here to Los Angeles.
他和一位叫格雷琴的公司的特工在一起
He's with an another company agent I know only as Gretchen.
就是杀害莎拉的那位特工
The same agent who murdered Sara.
这一切要在今天了结
This ends today.
我来这里寻求公正
I came here seeking justice.
当前司法系统无法提供的公正
The justice that I now know the system cannot provide.
所以如果你在读这封信的话...
So if you're reading this letter...
你就明白我为给莎拉报仇在所不惜
You'll know I died avenging Sara's death.
拿到数据卡之后
You get the data card.
我们立即把卡送达  然后马上离开
We drop it off in the racing form, and we get the hell out of there.
我们要把它交给谁
Who's the contact we're leaving it for?
公司要拿回数据卡  就这样
The Company wants the card back, period.
你就负责...
All you need to worry about...
载我们立即离开就好
Is getting this rig the hell out of there in a hurry.
这点我可以做到
Oh, I'll be getting it out of there.
你不用担心
Don't you worry about that.
只要你们尽快回来就行
You worry about getting your ass back in that seat in time.
如果你做成这件事  可以到我的房间...
If you pull this off, you can come up to my room later...
我是绝对不会拒绝的
and the word "no" won't be in my vocabulary.
确保我们拿到钱就好
Just make sure we get paid.
快去快回
In and out.
很高兴再次见到你
Good to see you again.
我也是
You, too.
很久没有你的消息了
Didn't hear from you for a while.
开始怀疑你是否还感兴趣了
Started to wonder if you were still interested.
当然  很感兴趣
I am, very much so.
我需要非常的小心
Well, I needed to approach this carefully.
我相信你一定会理解的
I'm sure you understand.
你为谁买的
Who you buying it for?
竞争对手
A competitor?
-其他国家  -杰森
-A foreign country? -Jason.
你知道我不可能告诉你的
You know I can't get into that.
我们已经谈了几个月了
Now, we've been negotiating this for months.
我答应了你所有的要求
I've jumped through all your hoops.
同意在这里和你见面
I've agreed to meet you here.
你到底想不想把数据卡卖给我
Do you want to sell the card to me or not?
很快回来
Be right back.
这块小塑料卡里有很多秘密
That's a lot of secrets on a little piece of plastic.
我给你一点建议
Let me give you a little bit of advice.
免费的建议
And this is on the house.
拿着那东西要小心点
Watch your step with that thing.
公司为了夺回它会不惜一切代价
The Company will do anything to get it back.
我难道不知道吗
Don't I know it.
-什么事  -你到底在干什么
-Yeah? -What the hell are you doing?
我们得马上离开这里
We got to get out of here.
我要把枪藏好
I need to hide the gun.
把枪带在身上
Take the gun with you!
快呀
Come on.
她在哪
Where is she?
迈克尔  你不明白
Michael, you don't understand.
给格雷琴打电话  让她马上来这儿
Call Gretchen, get her in here now.
你得相信我
You have to trust me.
我不是你的敌人  迈克尔
I'm not your enemy, Michael.
詹姆斯
James.
我们得快离开
We need to leave.
知道吗  无论如何...
You know, despite everything...
即使现在莎拉还活着 她也会让我别杀你
If Sara could weigh in right now. She'd tell me not to kill you.
她就是这样的人
That's the kind of person she was.
你就是把这样的人从我身边夺走了
That's the kind of person you took from me.
詹姆斯  难道你没告诉他吗
James, didn't you tell him?
-他刚刚才...  -闭嘴
-He walked in five... -Shut up!
格雷琴  看着我
Gretchen, look at me.
这个为了莎拉
This is for Sara.
我没杀莎拉
I never killed Sara.
我就知道你这样的人是不会坦然承认的
I wouldn't expect someone like you to take this with dignity.
我发誓她还活着
I swear to God she's alive.
别侮辱我  也别侮辱她
Don't insult me and don't insult her.
她逃掉了
She escaped.
我们清楚如果你知道  我们就没有任何筹码了
We knew if you found out we wouldn't have any leverage.
我编造了整件事
I fabricated the whole thing.
我哥哥看到了...
My brother saw...
箱子里的人头 是另一具尸体上的
From a cadaver.A head in a box!
你问问林肯他看到的到底是什么
You ask Lincoln what he really saw.
-听她说  迈克尔  -别对我撒谎
-Listen to her, Michael. -Don't lie to me.
我没撒谎  林肯上当了
I'm not lying to you. Lincoln bought it...
你也上当了  骗局成功了
You bought it, it worked.
迈克尔
Michael.
那她在哪
Then where is she?
我们出去后  我就告诉你
I'll tell you when we get outside.
现在  我们要先离开这里
Right now, we need to get out of here.
他们发现尸体了
They found the bodies.
-把枪给我  -她在撒谎
-Give me the gun. -She's lying.
是吗
Is she?
如果你扣动扳机  就永远不会知道答案了
If you pull that trigger, you'll never know.
杀了他  詹姆斯
Kill him, James.
闭嘴
Shut up.
她在哪
Where is she?
莎拉在哪
Where is Sara.
迈克尔
Michael.
如果你不把枪给我
If you don't give me that gun.
我就打爆你的头
I'm going to shoot you in the head.
我们走
Let's go.
我们在罗斯福酒店发现两具尸体
We got a double homicide at the Roosevelt Hotel.
莎拉
Sara
莫哈维沙漠  加州
Mojave desert, california.
你知道完美成功的行动和失败的行动...
Do you know the difference between a perfectly executed operation...
之间的区别吗
And a failed mission?
-长官  -取决于小团队的领导力
-Sir? -It's small unit leadership.
盟军用了两年半时间...
The Allies spent two and a half years...
策划进攻诺曼底
Planning the invasion of Normandy.
但在登陆日那天  一排滩头上的...
But on D-Day it came down to a handful of men...
一小股部队...
On a strip of beach...
来决定整个世界的命运
To decide the fate of the world.
格雷琴  我想说的是...
What I'm getting at, Gretchen...
即便是最好的计划...
Is even the best plan is only as good...
也需要有人去执行才会成功
As the moving parts on the ground executing it.
-将军  我们拿到了数据卡  -有什么问题吗
-General, we got your card. -what's the problem?
我们什么都没拿到  这是赝品
We have nothing. It's a duplicate.
几乎一模一样  但是个赝品
Almost flawless, but a duplicate.
这不可能  我看到...
That's impossible, I saw...
你知道夺回数据卡对我来说...
You know how important the retrieval of this card...
有多重要  格雷琴
Is to me, Gretchen.
你知道这是一个很可能...
You know that this is a security breach...
对公司产生灾难性的后果的安全隐患
that could have catastrophic ramifications for the Company.
我想唯一的可能就是...
The only thing I can think of...
当惠斯勒灭口的时候  有段时间可以做手脚
There was a blind spot when Whistler was hitting the target.
他可能复制了一份  并且还保留着原件
Maybe he made a duplicate and he still has the original.
你雇用了他
You hired him.
你对他委以重任
You kept him at the tip of the spear.
你坚持要把他从索纳监狱捞出来
You insisted that we get him out of Sona.
我们别无选择
We had to.
他当时已经和目标联系上
He had already made contact with the target.
当时  他是唯一的选择  长官
At that point, it was him or no one, sir.
你能从这件事中得到什么好处
What's your stake in all of this?
这件事与我无关  是惠斯勒一手策划的
I had nothing to do with it, Whistler acted on his own.
我向你发誓
I swear to you.
将军  我会补救的
General, I can fix this.
你训练了我
You trained me.
显然训练的不够好
Not well enough, apparently.
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
求求你
Please.
我在迪拜有一个帐户
I have a bank account in Dubai.
存有眼镜蛇2次行动中的贿金  是你的了
Left over from a slush fund from COBRA II, it's yours.
不  求求你  求求你
No, please, please.
巴拿马城  巴拿马
Panama City, Panama.
你好
Hello.
是我
Hey, it's me.
你在哪  兄弟
Where are you, man?
洛杉矶
Los Angeles.
你还好吗  迈克尔
You okay, Michael?
是的  我很安全
No, I'm, I'm safe.
谢天谢地
Thank God, thank God.
LJ和索菲亚怎么样
How's LJ and Sofia?
他们...我正看着他们呢
Yeah, they're...I'm staring at them right now in fact.
他们很好
They're fine.
听说索纳监狱的事了吗
You hear about Sona?
怎么了
What about it?
三天前被囚犯夷为平地了
Burned down three days back by the inmates.
囚犯暴乱了  没有贝里克  蒂博格和苏克雷的迹象
They rioted. no sign of Bellick, T-Bag, or Sucre.
苏克雷
Sucre?
他被抓了  我不知道原因
He got popped, I don't know how.
报纸上登出了囚犯名单...
I mean, the papers listed the names of the inmates...
监狱烧毁之前他在里面
And he was in there when it went down.
我找到惠斯勒和格雷琴了
I found Whistler and Gretchen...
格雷琴说...
Gretchen said...
她说莎拉还活着
She said Sara is still alive.
你究竟看到了什么  林肯
What did you see, Linc?
你是什么意思  迈克尔
What do you mean what did I see, Michael?
我要你告诉我  你到底看到了什么
I need you to tell me exactly what you saw.
迈克尔  莎拉已经死了
Michael, Sara's gone.
你说是在一个车库里  对吗  所以那一定很暗
You said it was in a garage, right? So it was dark.
对  是很暗
Yeah, it was dark.
但是如果你是在问  我是否拿起头...
But if you're asking me if I picked up the head...
检查是不是莎拉  不  迈克尔  我...
To check to see if it was Sara, no, Michael, I-I...
LJ说他...
LJ said he...
他只是听到他们杀了莎拉  对吗
He only heard them kill Sara, right?
你快回来吧  拜托
You just got to come back, please.
回来吧  我们一起...
Come back. Let's just...
一起开始新生活
Let's just start a new life.
替我向索菲亚问好
Tell Sofia I said hi.
告诉LJ...
And tell LJ...
告诉他  他叔叔很爱他
Tell him his uncle loves him.
迈克尔  别这样  求你了
Michael, don't do this, please.
亚利桑那沙漠  距离墨西哥边境5公里
Arizona Desert, 5 miles from the mexican border.
出来  出来
Out, out!
你该换一个好点的通风设备  朋友
You need some better ventilation back there, amigo.
想要翻译一下吗
Want to translate that?
不用了
Don't worry about it.
谢谢
Gracias.
你妈妈在哪儿
Where's your mom?
她会来的
She'll be here.
她回来的是什么意思
What do you mean she'll be here?
我们没时间了
We're running out of time.
-我得赶过去  -别担心
-I got to be up there. -Don't worry.
我妈妈不会让我失望的
My mom wouldn't let me down.
至少  目前还没有
At least, she hasn't yet.
布莱利  这里
Bradley, over here!
妈妈  妈妈
Mom! Mom!
我告诉过你的  别担心  你会准时到的
I told you! Don't worry, you'll make it there!
网址是什么
What is it called?
EuropeanGoldfinch.net
我们可以用它联系
It's what we can all use to communicate.
迈克尔・斯科菲尔德  我有莎拉的消息
MS: I have info on Sara.
迈克尔
Michael
别紧张  我是一个人
Don't worry, I'm alone.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
你最好的朋友在哪
So where's your new best friend?
我不知道
I don't know about that.
但惠斯勒并不是你想的那样
But Whistler's not who you think he is.
我们在联手对付公司
We're working together against the Company.
-是吗  -是的
-Yeah?  -Yeah.
那格雷琴呢
And what about Gretchen?
她也是同你一起的
She working with you?
他需要她来强化他的计划
He needed her to further his plan.
听着  如果他是公司的人  上次见面的时候...
Look, if the guy was Company, he'd have shot you dead...
他就该照她说的杀了你
Back at that conference like she wanted him to.
你到底有没有莎拉的消息
Do you have any information about Sara or not?
我们找个僻静一点的地方
Let's go somewhere a little more private.
我要你现在就告诉我
I want you to tell me right now.
我要你告诉我  就现在  就在这里
I want you to tell me right now, right here!
或者我们可以给格雷琴挂电话
Or we can get Gretchen on the phone.
格雷琴死了
Gretchen's dead.
她一直没出现
She never showed up.
来和我谈谈  拜托
Come and talk to me, please.
惠斯勒和我去会面为的是拿一张数据卡
Whistler and I were at that conference to get a data card.
那就像是公司的黑名册
It's like the Company's black book.
记录着他们所有的特工和行动
And it lists all their agents, all their operations.
他们称之为...
They refer to it as...
锡拉
"Scylla."
惠斯勒拿到手了
Whistler's got it.
阿历克斯  跟我谈谈莎拉的事
Alex, talk to me about Sara.
我只关心这点
That's all I care about.
我理解
I understand that.
我也只想回家跟妻儿团聚
I want nothing more than to get home to my wife and my son.
但只要公司在追杀我们...
But that's not gonna happen for either of us...
对我们来说  这都是可望不可求
With the Company out there trying to kill us.
你根本就没有莎拉的消息  对吧
You don't know anything about Sara, do you?
惠斯勒有  他告诉他知道
Whistler does, he tells me he does.
他想告诉你
And he wants to tell you.
但他要东西来交换
But he wants something in return.
什么  他想要什么
What? What does he want from me?
同你见面
To talk to you.
对于那晚的事  我很抱歉
I'm sorry about all that the other night.
当时如果有时间的话  我会解释的更清楚
If I had more time, I would've explained myself better.
当然
Sure.
我们来这做什么
What are we doing here?
-阿历克斯告诉你锡拉的事了  -是的
-Alex told you about Scylla? -Yes.
在我这里
I have it.
还差一步就可以读取里面的数据了
There's one last step involved in order to read the data.
要完成这一步  需要闯入一个戒备森严的地方
And that step involves breaking into a secured structure.
所以你需要我帮忙
So now you need my help.
对
Yeah.
我的书  我在索纳监狱丢的那本鸟类书...
My book, the bird book, the one I lost in Sona...
里面有能帮我们更容易的闯入的信息
Contained information that would've helped facilitate the break-in.
但即便没有  我们也能做到
but it can still be accomplished,
在你的帮助之下
With your help.
莎拉在哪
Where's Sara?
我唯一能确定的是...
The only thing I know for sure...
一周前  有消息吐露
A week ago, some information came through the wire.
莎拉在圣达菲买了一张巴士票
Sara may have bought a bus ticket in Santa Fe.
开往哪的
Headed where?
芝加哥
Chicago.
迈克尔  如果莎拉在芝加哥  她并不安全
Michael, if Sara's out there, she's not safe.
我们大家都不安全
None of us are.
公司知道原始数据卡在我们手里
The Company knows we still have the original card.
这就是格雷琴死了的原因
And that's why Gretchen was the first to go.
我想我们没什么好谈的了
I think we're done here.
迈克尔  我们只有这一次机会
Michael, We have a chance for once
将锡拉交给那些想搞垮公司的人
To get Scylla to people that want to take the Company down.
我不想再逃了  我们都不必再逃了
I don't want to run anymore. We won't have to run anymore.
之前的一个月  我一直沉浸在失去莎拉的痛苦和...
I spent the last month thinking Sara was dead...
害死莎拉的自责之中
and that it was my fault.
如果她在芝加哥  我要去找她
If she's out there, I'm gonna find her.
我只关心这个
That's all I care about.
只要一周就能搞定
This can be done within a week.
不到一周
Less.
至少让我给你们...
At least let me show you...
巴拿马城  巴拿马
Panama City, Panama
我会想念这对美腿的  美女
Oh, I'm gonna miss these gams, girl.
别走
Don't go.
这里可不是来自阿拉巴马的白人的家
This ain't no home for a white boy from Alabama.
他们到了  先生  行李都准备好了
They're here, seur, the bags are packed.
你遵守了对我的诺言
You kept your word to me.
你是第一个做到这点的人  谢谢
You're the first that's ever done that. Gracias.
你为何一定要找这个人
Why must you go after this man?
你可以选择不去的
You could choose not to.
在我的家乡  有个词叫做宿敌
Where I come from, there's something called a blood feud.
明白吗
Comprende?
是的
Yes.
结果是迈克尔・斯科菲尔德...
Michael Scofield left me for dead...
很多次的都对我见死不救
One too many times, as it turns out.
"小天使"用西班牙语怎么说
What is Spanish for "little angel"?
Angelita
Angelita.
再见  小天使
Adios, angelita.
确定合法吗
Is this legit?
当然  先生
Oh, Sí seur
您付了那么多钱  全程头等服务
For the money you're paying, first class, all the way.
这些人都可信吧
So these are coyotes one could trust.
当然  先生
Oh, Sí seur.
很好
Vamanos.
如你所见...
As you've seen...
你参与的这件事是很重要的
What you're entering into is quite serious.
我明白
I realize that.
你现在对此负责了
You're responsible for this now.
您不必担心
You have nothing to worry about.
稍后再谈
We'll talk soon.
现在该收拾残局了
It's time to clean up now.
彻底的
Thoroughly.
所有曾跟惠斯勒接触过的人
Everyone who was close to Whistler.
斯科菲尔德
Scofield.
马宏  布鲁斯
Mahone, Burrows.
布鲁斯还在巴拿马
Burrows is still in Panama.
都干掉
Clean up.
杜兰哥  科罗拉多
Durango, Colorado.
喂
Hello.
你好  帕姆
Hi, Pam.
你...
Where...
你在哪
Where are you?
你知道的...
Uh, you know...
跟从前一样  还在事件的漩涡当中
In the middle of it, as usual.
还在巴拿马
Panama still?
不  不在
No, no.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
很好
Definitely.
你呢
Are you?
很好
Yes.
卡梅伦呢
And Cameron?
他很好
He's fine.
我得告诉你  帕姆
I have to tell you, Pam, you know.
为了我们能在一起  我有个计划
I had a plan for all of us to be together.
而且...
And...
我是不会放弃的
I'm not gonna stop working on it.
你想和我们在一起的话  干嘛还需要计划呢
Why do you need a plan if you want to be with someone?
去和他们在一起就是了
You just be with them.
除非你是认真的  否则别这么说
Don't say that unless you mean it.
因为为了和你们在一起  我会不惜一切
'Cse I'll turn this world upside down to get back to you.
所以除非你是认真的  否则别这么说
So don't say it unless you mean it.
我是认真的
I mean it.
好
Okay.
别这样  宝贝
Come on, babe.
我讨厌芭蕉  你知道的
I-I hate plantains, you know that.
我尝过你的辣汉堡了
I try your chili burger.
辣汉堡  你喜欢辣汉堡
Chili-chili burger? You loved the chili burger.
好  我会...
Okay, I'm gonna...
用妈妈的独家秘方来做
Make them with my mom's special recipe.
你妈妈的独家秘方
Your mom's special recipe?
你会喜欢的
You'll love it.
是吗
Really?
是的  你会喜欢的  相信我
Yeah! You'll love them, trust me.
非常美味
It's delicious.
我们快离开这  把东西放下
Let's get out of here. Drop 'em.
我们走  拉着我
Let's go, give me your hand.
LJ, 我们走
LJ, let's go.
对  跟我走
Yeah, come with me.
林肯  怎么回事
Lincoln, what's going on?
爸爸
Dad.
我们已经安全了啊
We're safe now.
-放松  -不  我看到有人
-Relax. -No, I saw someone.
像是公司的人  我很确定
Looks like Company, I'm sure of it.
我们走吧  好吗
Let's just go, okay?
我们走
Let's go.
我们会没事的
We'll be fine.
好吧  好吧
All right, all right.
好
Okay.
走
Let's go.
退后
Get back.
爸爸
Dad!
爸爸  我们快跑
Dad, we have to run.
走  快离开这儿
Go. Get out of here.
快
Run!
快走
Get going!
林肯
Lincoln!
我找阿历克斯
I'm looking for Alex.
我不知道他在哪儿
I don't know where he is.
不知道
No?
No.
我们已经离婚快两年了
Uh, we've been divorced for almost two years now.
好几个月都没有联系了
We haven't had contact in months.
我想现在可能不同了  他回美国了
I would think that might change now that he's back in the U.S.
我真受不了你们这群人  是联邦探员吗
I am so sick of you people, what are you a fed?
以为可以不断骚扰我们吗
Thinking that you can keep on harassing...
我不是政府官员  帕姆
I'm not with the government, Pam.
妈妈  你能来一下吗
Mom, could you come here?
我们没什么好谈的
We're done talking.
布鲁斯・班尼特
Bruce Bennett.
你知道我是谁吗
Do you know who this is?
知道
I do.
我在找莎拉  然而现在...
I'm looking for Sara, and right now...
你是我能想到的唯一能帮我的人
You're the only person I can think of who can help me.
等一下
Hold on.
你在哪
Where are you?
我回芝加哥了
Back in Chicago.
你有她的消息吗
Have you heard from her?
半小时后到德雷克酒店门口见我
Meet me in front of the Drake Hotel in a half hour.
请告诉我  她还活着吗
Please just tell me, is she alive?
你是迈克尔・斯科菲尔德吗
Are you Michael Scofield?
是的  我是
Yes, I am.
-把手放到头后  -迈克尔  迈克尔
-Hands on your head. -Michael, Michael
迈克尔・斯科菲尔德
Michael Scofield
我是国土安全局的特工当・赛尔夫
Special Agent Don Self, Homeland Security.
詹姆士・惠斯勒被杀的时候  你在场吗
Were youhere when James Whistler was killed?
不是我干的
I didn't kill him.
我知道不是你干的
I know you didn't.
他曾是一位为公司工作了...
He was an independent contractor.
差不多10年的独立签约人
Who worked for the Company for about ten years.
公司派他追寻遗失的锡拉的下落
He was assigned to retrieve Scylla once it went missing.
你知道锡拉是什么吗
Do you know what Scylla is?
是公司的黑名册
It's the Company's little black book.
他本该拷贝一份交给我
So he was going to make a copy of it and give it to me.
你想要我做什么
What do you want from me?
你将被判以重罪
You're looking at major time.
你知道的  对吗
You know that, right?
你觉得如果让你摆脱干系...
So how would you like to walk away from it all...
全身而退如何
not do a day?
-用什么交换  -锡拉
-In exchange for...? -Scylla.
好  莎拉・唐克雷蒂  最后出现在巴拿马
All right. Sara Tancredi, last seen in Panama.
如果你帮我找到她...
If you help me find her...
也许我们可以做交易
Maybe we've got a deal.
对不起  她的事不归我管  我只管锡拉
I'm sorry, she's not my department, Scylla is.
那你自己去找吧
Then go find it yourself.
在我看来...
It seems to me...
美国政府应该比要被判以重罪的人...
The U.S. government should have a little more reach...
更有手段
Than someone who's looking at major time.
如果要找莎拉的话  迈克尔
To perform the operation, Michael.
需要大约20个...
That would require signatures...
不同部门领导的签名才行
From about 20 different department heads.
你要赌赌  他们之中至少有一个是公司的人吗
Do you want to bet at least one of them is Company?
唯一可行的办法是...
The only way this is going to work...
通过编外人员  地下行事
Is via freelancer, off the books.
听起来很复杂
It sounds complicated.
交易告吹
I'll take a pass.
我提供给你的是一个免除15年刑期的机会...
I'm giving you an opportunity to avoid 15 years in jail...
更不用说你哥哥所面临的了
Not to mention the time that your brother's facing.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
公司想把他弄出巴拿马
The Company tried to take him out in Panama.
他反抗了
He, um... reacted.
很显然
Apparently.
但我刚刚同...
But I just made a deal...
巴拿马当局达成协议...
With the Panamanian authorities...
让他返回美国服刑
For him to serve out his time in the U.S.
他随时可能到达
He should be touching ground any time now.
你能认出这笔迹吗
You recognize this handwriting?
是你父亲的
This is your father's.
在他生命的最后两年里...
He spent the last two years...
一直在追查这件事
of his life going after this very thing.
你相信命运吗  迈克尔
Do you believe in fate, Michael?
我要跟我哥哥谈一谈
I think I'd like to talk to my brother.
不
Oh, no.
怎么回事...
What's going...?
站住  站住  你不能进去
Stop! Stop! You don't want to go in there.
你不能进去
You don't want to go in there.
我们很遗憾
We're sorry, sorry.
天啊  她...
God, she's...
莉拉・玛丽亚・苏克雷
Lilah Maria Sucre.
她用了我的姓
She gave her my name?
我是你爸爸哦
Soy tu papa.
你出卖我
You're setting me up?
苏克雷  你不能再拖累玛丽克鲁兹了
Sucre, you can't keep bringing Maricruz down.
你不能再这样对她了
You can't do this to her anymore.
-没事的  -等等  别...
-It's OK. -Wait. Don't...
苏克雷  不要
Sucre, don't...
快  快
Go! Go!
天啊
Oh, boy.
我们完蛋了
We're screwed.
你们知道为什么斯科菲尔德...
You know why Scofield...
在我身边的时候总是苦恼不堪吗
Gets all twisted up when he's around me?
我们很相似  可他却不想承认这一点
We're the same, and he just can't stand it.
这让他近乎疯狂
Drives his ass crazy.
我们有同样聪明的头脑
We got the same brilliant mind.
同样与生俱来的领导能力
the same natural-born leader tendency.
同样万里挑一的个人魅力  对吧
the same one-in-a-million-type charisma, yes?
他却总是看不起我
He just gonna look down his nose at me?
你要怎么找到他
How you gonna find him?
这个
This.
你们都喜欢鸟
You're both into birds?
不
No, no.
它要么带我找到他  要么就是他找到我
It's either gonna take me to him, or he to me.
我就知道
I just know it.
如果我是你  我就忘掉斯科菲尔德
If I was you, I'd forget about this Scofield.
你有大把的钱  瞧  我是说...
You have plenty of money. See? I mean...
你包里装了多少钱
How much money you have in that bag?
为何不管好你们自己的事
Why don't you just mind your own beeswax, huh?
你就把这破车...
You just keep pointing...
一直往北开就行  好吗
this jalopy northbound, all right?
带我回美国
Get me back to the land 'o cotton.
当然
Of course.
准备好了
Ready.
政府只有几个人知道这次的行动
Only a few people in government will know of the operation.
必须得这样...
It has to stay that way...
否则大家都会处于危险之中  包括我
Or people's lives will be in danger, mine included.
把公司搞跨听起来不太像是两个人的工作  对吧
Taking down the company sounds a little bit more than a two-man job, no?
我会找人帮助你们
I'm going to get you help.
你不是说你不能相信任何人吗
I thought you said, you couldn't trust anybody.
是  不过也许你们可以
Yeah, but maybe you can.
你们的两个朋友...
All right, two of your cohorts...
费尔南多・苏克雷和布拉德・贝里克被捕了
Fernando Sucre, and Brad Bellick were arrested.
他们都面临牢狱之灾
They're both facing time.
亚历山大・马宏在科罗拉多的监狱里
And Alexander Mahone is in a Colorado jail cell.
很好  就让他待在那好了
Good, let him sit there.
想要成功  我们需要马宏
You're going to need Mahone if you want to make this happen.
他曾经和惠斯勒合作过
He was working with Whistler.
我也会加入
And you'll have me.
如何  无论你们需要什么  我都会提供
Okay? Whatever you need, I'll provide.
惠斯勒还提过第二步计划
Whistler also said something about a second step,
关于闯入某个地方
Something about a break-in.
是的  卡里储存着所有的数据
Yeah, the card has all the data on it.
但是被加密了
But it's encrypted.
一旦你开始行动
Once you get your hands on it.
你就必须找到一个进入...
You're going to need to find a way to break...
公司总部的办法
Into the Company's headquarters.
这是解密那张卡的唯一办法
It's the only way to unlock what's on the card.
总部在哪
Where's the building?
-洛杉矶  -洛杉矶的哪里
-L.A. -Where in L.A.?
我不清楚
I don't know.
所以  我们要找到不知在何处的数据卡
So, we've got a data card, which could be anywhere.
然后闯入一个...
And we've got to break into a building...
确切地址不明的总部大楼
The location of which has yet to be determined.
很简单
Simple enough.
你曾经两次成功越狱
You've broken out of two penitentiaries.
我想闯入一座总部大楼...
I'm thinking, uh, breaking into a building...
对你来说应该不是太难吧
Isn't too far outside your wheelhouse.
你怎么知道我们父亲的
How do you know our dad?
他通过线人了解到我可以信任
He heard from contacts that I could be trusted.
你爸爸是个好人
Your father was a good man.
为什么是现在
Why now?
听着  我已经追查公司5年了
Look, I've been going after the Company for five years.
好吗  昨天惠斯勒被杀后...
Okay? When Whistler was killed yesterday...
整个调查行动都应该停止了
The plug was going to be pulled on the entire operation.
但是...
But, uh...
我说服我的上司再试最后一次
I convinced my superiors to give it one more chance.
这就像是你的保住饭碗行动
So this is like job security for you?
什么
What's that?
所以当我们冲锋陷阵的时候...
Well, when we go out there and risk our necks...
你就能确保你的退休金了
You can collect your pension.
不  不  林肯
No, no, no, Lincoln.
有些人关心的是自己的工作
Okay, some people still care about their job.
有些人是在为这个国家而奋斗
Some people still fight for this country.
也许你太过于...
Maybe you've been a little too distracted...
固执己见  一意孤行了
Boosting car stereos and breaking heads to remember that.
如果我们参加的话...
If we do this deal...
事成之后
After it's done.
你就可以去找莎拉了  如果她还活着
You can look for Sara, if she's alive.
如果我们参加  在我有机会...
If we take this deal, we'll both be dead...
找她之前  我们就都会死的  林肯
Long before I get the chance, Linc.
你们一定有些有权有势的朋友
You guys must have some big-time friends.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
有人刚刚交了一笔...
Somebody just posted...
数额可观的保释金替你们保释
A significant amount of bail for both of you.
谁
Who?
我不知道  他们在外面
I don't know, but they're outside.
你们可以走了
You're free to go.
拿着  带上你爸爸的文件  里面有我的电话
Here, take your dad's file. My number's inside.
-我们不参加  -拿着吧
-We ain't doing this. -Just take it anyway.
这文件对我来说已经没有用了
This file, it means nothing to me anymore.
布鲁斯・班尼特
Bruce Bennett.
我们走吧
Let's go for a drive.
我以为再也见不到你了
I thought I'd never see you again.
我有东西要给你
I have something for you.
好啊
Okay.
你忘记这个了
You left this behind.
你把玫瑰找回来了
Is that what this is about?
是这个意思吗
You just getting me my rose back?
是的  我想我完成任务了
Yeah. I guess I'm done now.
我可以退休了
I can retire.
你会入狱多久
How much time are you looking at?
他们说要15年
They're saying 15 years.
我得确定一下
I have to find out for sure.
我听林肯说有个什么交易
I heard Lincoln say something about a deal.
不必坐牢
No jail time.
条件是弄跨公司
In exchange for taking down the Company.
如何弄垮
How?
这就是问题所在
Exactly.
我爱你
I love you.
我现在只知道这一点
That's all I know right now.
你难道不会向万能的主屈服吗
"Will you not yield to the immortal gods?"
噩梦不会觉醒
"That nightmare cannot die."
永不休止的罪恶
"Eternal evil itself."
没人能打败她  没有
"There is no fighting her, no."
没有力量能打败她
"No power that can fight her."
听我说  现在由你们自己做主了
Now, listen to me, it's up to you now.
逃跑是最好的办法
"All that avails is flight."
抱歉  我没想吓你
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to scare you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
想跟我聊聊吗
Do you want to talk about it?
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
不是
It's not.
告诉我是怎么回事
Tell me what happened.
是公司
It's just the Company.
这就是他们的所作所为
It's just what they do.
不仅是我
It wasn't just me.
上帝  你和LJ...
God, it was you and LJ and-and
还有林肯
Lincoln.
他们不会罢手的
And they won't stop.
我不知道该怎么办
and I don't know how to deal with that.
过来
Hey, come here.
过来  到我这儿来
Come here. Come here.
我们走!
Let's go!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
难以置信他们这么快就找到我们了
I can't believe they found us so fast.
我是不是该打电话给布鲁斯
Should I call, should I call Bruce
叫他找个安全的地方
And-and get some place safe?
没有地方是安全的
No place is safe.
除非我们弄垮公司  否则他们不会罢休的  林肯
They're not gonna stop unless we stop them. Linc?
你和我想的一样吧  让我们结束这一切
You are thinking what I'm thinking? Let's end this.
我不会再次丢下你不管的
But I'm not gonna leave you behind again.
喂
Yeah?
我们加入了
We're in.
你好  兄弟
Hey, papi.
林肯
Linc.
我不知道如何表达你让我加入的感激之情
I can't tell you how grateful I am for you including me.
是苏克雷给你担保的  贝里克
Well, Sucre vouched for you, Bellick.
他说在巴拿马 你是因为他才被抓的
He said you came through...For him down in Panama.
阿历克斯
Alex?
迈克尔
Michael.
你准备好了吗
You ready for this?
是的  我准备好了
Yeah. I am.
我听说惠斯勒的那本鸟类书籍里...
So I hear Whistler's bird book...
有我们要偷的东西的详细资料
Has details about what we need to steal.
是的
Yeah.
你知道在谁手里  对吧
You know who's got it, right?
求你了
Please.
我们会死在这里的
We'll die out here.
谢谢你的钞票  外国佬
Thanks for the cash, gringo.
全程头等服务
First class all the way.
你知道帝博格在哪儿吗
Do we have any idea where T-Bag is?
谁知道那狡猾的家伙在哪
That snake could be anywhere.
在洛杉矶  我们可以像犯人一样思考
When we're in L.A., we can think like convicts.
但却不能那样行事
We just can't act like them.
如果那么做  我们就死定了
If we do, we're done.
显而易见...
It goes without saying...
现在是退出的最后机会
This is your last chance to back out.
因为我无法保证的事情中...
'cause first on the list of things...
最重要的一点就是你们的命
I cannot guarantee you is your safety.
我们偏离原先的初衷...
We're all a long way...
太远了
From where this started.
但我向你保证的是...
But what I can guarantee you...
如果我们成功的话
Is that if we do this thing right.
就距离我们的目标更近了
We'll be close to where it ends.
就是自由
Freedom.
最终的自由
Finally.
你们俩  我们走吧
You two, let's go.
麦克
Hey, Mike?
莎拉怎么样了
What about Sara?
莎拉加入了
Sara's in.
好的  我们明天出发
All right, we're heading out tomorrow.
离开之前我要最后确认一些事
I have to finalize a few things before we go.
不玩阴谋  不耍花招
No games and no stunts.
否则的话  我保证...
Otherwise, I promise...
你会看到我完全不一样的另一面
You're gonna see a whole different side of me.
我们也是
Likewise.
假身份证
Fake IDs.
不错的开始
It's a good start.
但有些东西无法作假
But there are some things you can't fake.
有些东西...
And there are some things...
无法隐藏
You can't hide.
明白我的意思吗
Know what I mean?
你对痛觉的忍受度有多高
How high is your threshold for pain?
你确定不用镇痛剂吗
You sure you don't want a sedative?
现在是最痛的时候了
We're gonna go into the night.
感觉如何
How do you feel?
不知为何  变轻了
Lighter somehow.
我都不知道该如何搞垮公司
Look, I don't know how we're gonna take them down.
我甚至不知道他们的身份
I don't even know who they are.
我只知道一件事...
But I do know one thing...
公司将为他们对你的所作所为付出代价
The Company's gonna pay for what they did to you.
我们走吧
Let's go.
你确定你要加入
You sure you're up for this?
如果我们...
If we can...
能一起的话  是的
do it together, yeah.
-好  -当然
-OK. -Absolutely.
AC-130运输机  他们要干什么...
AC-130? What do they want...
难道让我们跳伞吗
Want us to parachute out of this thing?
那家伙找了空军协助
This guy called in a favor to the Air Force.
我们总不能坐民航飞机  对吧
It's not like we can be flying commercial, you know?
如果你们成功拿到锡拉
If you're successful with obtaining Scylla.
不仅可以免除牢狱之灾  而且你们会为...
You'll not only avoid jail time, but you can take great pride...
铲除对这个国家民主的最大威胁...
In knowing you helped dismantle this country's greatest threat...
而感到自豪
To its own democracy.
如果在执行任务过程中身亡...
If you're killed while doing so...
将会被赋予体面的葬礼
A proper funeral will be provided.
但如果你们试图逃跑...
But if you try to escape...
不但没有葬礼
You will have no funeral.
什么都不会得到
You will have nothing,
你们会被追捕...
And you will be apprehended and buried where...
并被就地处决
We find you.
我衷心希望我们能互相理解
I sincerely hope we understand each other.
你最好信守诺言
You better hold up your end of the deal.
我们走
let's go!
洛杉矶  加利福尼亚
Los Angeles, California.
他们答应您的要求了  将军
They are in projection you asked for, general.
线路安全  说吧
You clear, go ahead.
事情有些复杂了
There has been a complication.
布鲁斯和斯科菲尔德已经被转移到...
Burrows and scofield had been transferred to...
我看过报纸了
I read the newspapers,
你不必告诉我头版头条的新闻
You don't have to tell me what's in the headlines.
他们到底被关在哪座监狱还不得而知
The exact penitary where they are been held is under disclosed.
不过肯定是联邦级的  重型监狱
But you can guarantee it'll be the federal, supremax.
不必再汇报了
No more updates.
干掉他们后再给我电话
Call me when they are dead.
欢迎来到洛杉矶
Welcome to Los angles.
问题是  越狱过不止一次的人...
As it turns out, Men who have escaped not one...
被认为是有一定的潜逃隐患的
But two penitaries are considered as a bit of flight risks.
所以我们需要时刻了解...
So we need to know where you are...
你们的位置和行动
And what you're doing at all times.
这些是脚踝全球定位跟踪器
These are GPS ankle monitors.
现在过来拿一个带上
Now step up, take one and put it on.
我不带
I ain't wearing that.
让我们说清楚
Let's make this clear.
我是你们的盟友
I'm your ally.
但更重要的是  我是你们的老板
But more importantly, I'm your boss.
也就是说  如果这次行动失败
Which means if this fails.
和你们比起来 我会面临更大的麻烦
It's my ass on the line as much If not more than yours,
所以从现在开始
so from this point on.
我让你们做什么  你们就做什么
If I ask you to do something, you do it.
我让你们说什么
If I ask you to say something.
你们就说什么
You say it.
我让你们带上跟踪器
And if I ask you to put on a monitor.
你们就带上跟踪器
You put on a monitor.
目前为止所有人都认为...
As far as the general public is concerned...
你们被关押在美国境内某个重型监狱里
You're being contained in a supermax facility somewhere In the United States
所以要避免无谓的解释
So to avoid any messy explanations.
避免被公司发现
And stay off the Company's radar.
你们要低调行事并且保持警惕
You need to keep your heads down and your ears open.
我们提供了手机  衣物和洗漱用品
We've provided cell phones, clothing, and toiletries.
所有的基本必需品都已准备好了
All the basic necessities to get you up and running.
你让这些家伙进来之前都搜过身了吧
You patted these guys down before you let them in, right?
我可不想被暗算
Cause I can't be getting shanked or shivved.
他是谁
Who's this?
他是罗兰・格伦
This is Roland Glenn.
他会协助你们
He'll be assisting you.
我们的队伍已经满员了
We've already got our team.
不是  斯科菲尔德  这是我的队伍
No, Scofield, see, this is my team.
罗兰和你们一样...
And Roland's working off...
也要干活来免除牢狱之灾
A sentence just like the rest of you.
事实上  就对锡拉保安的严密程度而言...
In fact, with the amount of security that's gonna be around Scylla...
罗兰的专长是必要的
Roland's expertise will be a necessity.
所以  如果没有其它问题
So, if no more questions.
我们开始寻找锡拉的工作吧
Let's get to work on finding Scylla.
那个第二步怎么办
What about that second step?
闯入的问题呢
What about the break-in?
我来负责第二步  好吗
You let me worry about step two, okay?
你把精力放在寻找锡拉就好
You just worry about finding Scylla.
关于从哪入手  我有个想法
I've got an idea where to start.
非常棒  亚历山大
That's excellent, Alexander.
你瞧  还有人在思考
See, there's a man who's thinking.
好了  大家开始工作吧
All right, let's let these men get to work.
祝我们大家都好运
Good luck, to all of us.
既然我是第一个到的...
Since I was here first I think I'll...
如果大家没意见  那个最舒服的房间就归我了
Just go ahead and grab that S.S. bedroom, if that's cool.
-莎拉  -怎么
-Sara. -Yeah?
那个位置归你
You take the bunk.
当这一切结束以后
You know, when this is, when this is all done.
你和我  我们要做个了断
You and me, we're gonna settle up.
很明显
All right, obviously.
这里的恩怨很多
There's a lot of history in this room.
这显而易见
That's a given.
但如果我们要完成任务
But it we're gonna pull this off.
需要所有人的努力
It's gonna take all of us.
我们要团结一致
We got to work together.
如果谁有问题  现在就说出来
So if anyone has a problem, get it out now.
谁想要和别人解决恩怨...
You want to clear the air with someone...
就是现在了
Now's the time.
好的
All right.
我们开始干活吧
Let's get to work.
惠斯勒的任务是把数据卡...
Whistler's assignment was to drop off this data card...
锡拉交给一名公司高管
This 'Scylla' to a Company Executive.
一个被他称为"持卡者"的人
Someone he referred to as "The Cardholder."
他的任务是保护数据卡
And his job was to-to protect it.
保证它的安全
To keep it safe.
目前  我还不知道他是谁
Now, I didn't see who he was.
不过我见过他的司机
But I got a look at his driver.
他的司机
His driver?
你想描绘这家伙的脸...
You want to sketch this guy's face...
再和一千万洛杉矶人比对吗
And match it up to 10 million people in Los Angeles?
这太有才了
Well, that's just great.
我不仅看到了他的脸
I saw more than just the guy's face.
当其他的司机都在胡扯闲聊的时候
All the drivers were hanging around, talking shop.
但这个家伙  独自站在旁边
But this guy, he was standing by himself.
两腿微分  双手背后
Legs apart, hands behind his back.
静止不动  他是位退伍军人
At rest, he's former military.
他车的底盘比其他的都低
His car rides a little lower than the rest of 'em.
也许是由于注重安全性的...
Probably signifies private security...
防弹玻璃增加车身重量的原因
Weighed down by bulletproof siding.
他的衣服  仅凭警察的工资或...
His suit, you don't buy a suit like that...
周末兼职司机的外块  是买不起的
On a cop's salary or pulling weekend gigs as a driver.
说明他是全职
That means he's full-time.
高薪
He's highly paid.
如果请我们的朋友  赛尔夫先生查一下...
You ask our friend Mr. Self to run tax records...
生活在洛杉矶45至55岁之间的...
On the 45- to 55-year-old white males...
领取军方退休金  并且从私人保安公司赚取...
In Los Angeles drawing a military pension...
6位数以上年薪的白人男性税务记录的话...
And taking six figures from a private security company...
就能把范围从1000万人缩小到大概50人
And you narrow your field from 10 million till about 50.
然后我就能从中找出那个家伙了
And then I can pick the guy out from there.
找到司机  就能找到持卡者
Find the driver, you find the Cardholder.
墨西哥沙漠  距美国边境60英里
Mexican Desert, 60 miles south of US border.
我们已经好几天不吃不喝了
We haven't ate or drank anything for days.
我不想死在这里
Oh, I don't want to die out here.
我们不会死的  桑乔
We ain't gonna die, Sancho.
-我们不会死的  -好的
-Hey, hey, we ain't gonna die. -OK
我们只需要找到...
We just gotta find...
那个叫什么  仙人掌指南针就好
What's called, a compass cactus.
因为仙人掌总是向南倾斜的
Due to the fact it always leans toward the south.
里面是鲜美的果肉  我们可以填饱肚子
Inside there's delicious fruit which'll fill our bellies.
而且  我们会知道哪边是南
Plus, we find out which way is south.
我们得找到哪边是北才行
We're gonna find out which way is north.
明白吗
Comprender?
这样吧
Tell you what.
我们在这休息一会如何
Why don't we rest here for a while, huh?
等晚上凉快一点再走
Travel at night when it's cooler.
对  这主意不错
Si, that sounds good.
我们到那之后怎么办
What are we gonna do when we get there?
到圣地亚哥
To San Diego.
你是说等迈克尔为他...
You mean after Michael pays...
对我所做的卑鄙无耻的事付出代价之后吗
For the vile he's transgressed upon me?
我还在考虑这是什么意思
I'm still trying to figure that out.
和国土安全局合作真不错
Nice to work with Homeland.
联邦调查局想得到这些信息得大费周折
The FBI would take days to gather this intel.
联邦调查局该雇用我
Well, the FBI should'a hired me
无论什么资料  我都能在25分钟内搞到手
Cause I could've gotten whatever info you wanted in 25 minutes tops.
你是黑客吗
Are you some kind of hacker?
我以设计硅光刻为生
I design silicon lithography for personal gain.
他是个身份窃贼
He's an identity thief.
他是个蠢货
He's a douche.
你坐一边去
Hey, why don't you sit in the corner.
需要你的时候我们会叫你
And we'll get you when we need you.
就是他
This is him.
他就是那个司机
That's the driver.
现在怎么办
Now what?
他能带我们找到持卡者
Well, he takes us to the Cardholder.
持卡者能带我们找到锡拉
And the Cardholder takes us to Scylla.
你可以把我扔在监狱里不管的
You could have left me there, in jail.
是可以还是应该
Could have or should have?
也许都是
Maybe both.
你是在感谢我吗  阿历克斯
Are you thanking me, Alex?
-我不知道  -别在意了
-I don't know. -Don't bother.
我们是需要你来
You're here because we needed you.
-不是想要你来  -就是他
-Not because we wanted you. -That's him.
就是家伙
That's the guy.
那是什么  看起来像是私人保镖
What's that, looks like private security?
这里就像是城堡一样
It's like a fortress.
慢点  慢点
Slow down, slow down.
我们在找的东西
This thing we gotta get.
在里面吗
It's in there?
运动传感器  警报系统
Motion sensors, alarm systems.
武装保安
Armed guards.
神不知鬼不觉的进去再出来
In and out of that place without anybody knowing.
你最好做个完美的计划  迈克尔
You better have one hell of a plan, Michael.
所以基本上根本无法潜入那个地方
So, basically there's no freaking way to break in to the place.
不可能那么快  不可能不被发现
Not quickly, not without being seen.
周边建筑呢  有什么地方我们可以...
What about the neighbors, somewhere we can be staged from...
挖地道钻过去
You know, go under and up?
最近的一处在这里  路对面
Closest neighbor is here, across the street.
就算这样也要数周时间
And even that would take weeks.
政府放出我们被关押在重型监狱的假消息...
The government's story about us being held in a supermax...
不会隐瞒太久
Will only last so long.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
我是说  如果有人发现事实怎么办
I mean, then what if somebody finds out we're not.
或许我们不需要闯入那所房子
What if we don't have to be in the house?
如果那个数据卡  锡拉如此重要
If the card, this Scylla is so important.
也许那家伙是随身携带的
Maybe the guy is carrying it on him.
根据政府公共记录
Well, according to public records.
该物业的主人名为斯图亚特・塔克豪恩
The owner of the estate's name is Stuart Tuxhorn.
他是一家名为斯皮克托利姆公司的总裁
And he's a CEO of a company called Spectroleum.
这样的大人物一定是24小时有保镖贴身保护的
Heavy hitter like that's gonna have security 24-7.
我们要在神不知鬼不觉的情况下...
And we gotta get this thing...
把数据卡偷走  对吧
Without anyone knowing it's gone, right?
就算他随身携带  我们如何行事
So even if he's got it on him, how do we get it off him?
我们不必偷走数据卡
You don't steal the card.
复制一份就行
You copy it.
现在你们对我的话感兴趣了  对吧
Oh, now you're interested in what I gotta say, right?
复制一份更难做到
Copying it will make it harder.
不止要偷
Not only do you have to steal it.
而且要还  天才
You have to return it, genius.
有我便不必了  哥们
Only if you don't got me, hombre.
那是什么
What's that?
我就是因为这个被抓的
This is the reason I got busted.
你偷了个手机吗
Oh, you stole the cell phone?
不  不
Oh, yeah, yeah, no.
偷手机就要被关重型监狱  你开玩笑吧
I'm looking at federal time cause I stole a cell phone, seriously?
我发明了这个
I invented this
所以我不必去偷
So that I don't have to steal.
它看起来像是个手机  但实际上它...
It looks like a cell phone but it's really like...
像是个数码黑洞
A digital black hole.
这是可以接受10英尺内所有电子数据的...
Wireless hard drive that swallows up any electronic data...
无线接收器
Within ten feet of it.
比如
Like what?
可以接收在星巴克...
Like the account info...
无线上网的人的帐户信息
Of anyone at Starbucks with a latte and a laptop.
可以接收加油站使用信用卡的顾客的密码
Like the PIN number of any credit card used at a gas pump.
用它我可以轻轻松松的用一只手...
I can walk out of here and get the identities...
在十分钟内得到十个人的...
And financial statements of ten people in ten minutes...
身份及账户信息
On a slow day, with one hand on my junk.
锡拉里面的信息呢
And the information embedded in Scylla?
只要能接近...
If we can get close enough...
就是我们的了
It's ours.
这个数目  你能接受吗
Is this number acceptable to you?
1万人
10,000 people?
-可以  -很好
-Yes. -Good.
现在你加入了
Now that you're on board.
我们今天就可以传达行动命令了
We can issue the op-order today.
他上路了
He's on his way.
好的  稍等
All right, hold on.
莎拉  是我
Sara, it's me.
大家都已就绪
Everybody's on.
在我运行装置的时候
Now, while I'm monitoring the device.
我无法知道...
I'm not gonna be able to see...
拷贝的具体内容
Exactly what data's being copied.
但就像从网上下载A片一样
But, like downloading quality porn from the Internet.
进度条会显示什么时候会传输完毕
Progress bar's gonna tell me when it's time to rock and roll.
他们需要待在范围内多久
How long do they need to stay in range?
像这样的加密数据需要至少2分钟
Encrypted data like this is gonna take at least two minutes.
他来了
Here he comes.
苏克雷  该你了
Sucre, you're on.
好运
Good luck.
先生  您可否不要靠近车
Sir, would you mind stepping away from the vehicle?
怎么样了  罗兰
Talk to me, Roland.
我什么都没收到  伙计
I got nothing, man.
上次我这么努力的还是在...
Last time I had this little action...
艰难的通过五年级考试的时候
I was dry humping my way through fifth grade.
冷静点
Calm down.
先生
Sir.
离车远点
Step away from the vehicle!
好的  哥们  放松点  我们不必如此激动
Okay, bro, just relax, we don't have to get all excited.
现在你会说英语了
You speak English now.
只会一点  但是...
Only a little, but...
现在怎么样了
How about now?
不行
Nada.
试着再靠近一点儿
Try to get closer to them.
再靠近  他就得进车里了
If he was any closer, he'd be in the car.
我知道你的小把戏了  混蛋
I get your little act, Pedro.
故意撞车
Hit the brakes.
让有钱人赔钱  你就不用修车了
let the rich guy pay for damage you don't intend to fix.
给他点钱我们好走
Just give the man some money so we can leave.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
他在那  我想塔克豪恩在车里
He was there, I think Tuxhorn was in the car.
-我们到底收到没有  -没有
-So did we get it or not? -Nope.
什么都没有
Nothing.
我能效劳吗
Can I help you?
你怎么找到我的
So how did you find me?
我一直在跟踪你
I never lost you.
新鼻子让我有点吃惊  但是...
The, uh, the new nose threw me a bit, but...
你想要什么  当
What do you want, Don?
我还有客人
I got customers.
从前  你和公司合作的时候...
Look, back in the days, when you worked with the Company.
为公司卖命
Well, for the Company.
我负责公司的经营预测
I did economic forecasts of their operations.
我是说  我不是那些人中的一员...
I mean, I wasn't one of the guys...
但你有人脉
But you had access.
得了吧  上次我帮你
Come on, the last time I helped you.
除了花10万美金做个手术以外...
The only thing I got out of it...
我什么都没有得到
Was plastic surgery and a $100,000 pay cut.
所以  要么你买一辆大马力的顶级豪华车
so either you buy one of these exceptional family cars
要么你就滚蛋
Or you leave me the hell alone.
我知道锡拉的事
I know about Scylla
而且我在找它
And I'm going after it.
我知道你很疯狂
You know, I knew you were crazy.
但不知道你也很蠢
I didn't know you were stupid, too.
假如说我能拿到数据卡
Well, let's just say I was able to get hands on it.
据我理解  锡拉只有在插在...
It's my understanding that Scylla could only be used...
藏在公司内部某处的...
If it's plugged into a decoder box...
解码器上才能被读取
That's hidden in one of the Company facilities.
我说的对吗
Am I right?
我希望我能帮忙
You know, I wish I could help.
但我爱莫能助
but I can't.
不  你会帮忙的  贾斯帕
No, you are helping, Jasper.
问题只是在我把你当着同事的面...
Just a matter of whether you do it before or after...
羞辱一番之前还是之后罢了
I shame you in front of your coworkers here.
告诉我公司把解码器藏在哪  贾斯帕
Tell me where the Company keeps the box, Jasper.
可能在任何地方  我不知道
Could be anywhere, I don't know.
总有人知道吧
Somebody does.
对吧
Right?
你认识的某个人
Somebody that you might have access to.
如果你一意孤行
You know, if you go down this road.
你的政府职位也保不了你
Your government job won't protect you.
那我最好别被抓住  对吧
Then I better not get caught, right?
如果我不快点找到些吃的
If I don't find something to eat soon.
我真不知道该怎么办
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
我们撑不过去的
We're not gonna make it.
我们得不停的说话  桑乔
We just got to keep talking, Sancho.
把注意力从饥饿的肚皮和...
Keep our brains focused on something other than...
干裂的嘴唇上转移开  好吗
Our empty bellies and our dry mouths, okay?
来吧
Come on.
从你最喜欢的颜色说起
Let's start with, uh, your-your favorite color.
你他妈的在干嘛
Hell you doing?!
我太饿了  泰迪
I'm hungry, Teddy.
与其我们两个都死在这
Why should the both of us die out here.
不如一个人牺牲自己  成全对方
When one of us could help the other one survive?
你不该这样做  拜托
You don't want to do this. Please.
我会给你个痛快的  我保证
I'll make it quick. I promise!
桑乔
Sancho.
Sancho!
你为什么非要做这样的...
Why'd you have to go and do something so...
这么说塔克豪恩没把卡带在身上
So Tuxhorn doesn't keep the card on him.
一定在里面  对吧
It must be in there, right?
听着  想要潜进房子而不被发现...
Look, there's no way we're getting...
是不可能的
In that house without being seen.
我知道
I know.
如果卡在房子里  我们如何拷贝
Well, if the card's in there, how we gonna copy it?
不是我们
We're not.
她替我们做
She's gonna do it for us.
在看什么呢
What're you reading?
没人能打败她
"There is no fighting her."
没有力量能打败她
"No power can fight her.
飞行是最好的办法
"All that avails is flight."
这是荷马的...
That's homer...
《奥德赛》中的片段
That's from The Odyssey.
-这些是我父亲文件中的东西  -是的
-Is this from my father's folder? -Yeah.
这也解释了为何锡拉听起来这么耳熟
And it explains why Scylla sounded so familiar.
如果我没弄错的话  这是书中...
If I'm not mistaken, it's from that chapter in the book...
奥德赛被告知...
Where Odysseus is told...
他要勇敢的面对一个叫锡拉的妖怪
He has to confront a monster known as Scylla.
他为什么要写这个
Wonder why he wrote this down.
我说的不一定正确  但我相信...
I could be wrong, but I believe...
奥德塞斯被告知...
Odysseus is told that in order to...
要继续前行  打倒锡拉...
Continue on his path, to pass Scylla...
必须牺牲他的六名手下
It'll require the sacrifice of six of his men.
否则他只有放弃他的旅途
His only other alternative is to abandon his path.
他选择了牺牲手下
And he chooses to make the sacrifice.
真是个艰难的选择
Well, it's a hell of a choice.
我不知道我能否做出选择
One I'm not sure I'm comfortable making.
莎拉  关于明天女佣的那个计划
Sara, um, about tomorrow the plan, the housekeeper.
如果你为难的话
If you're not up to it.
不  不  我可以
No, no, I am.
芝加哥  伊利诺斯州
Chicago, Illinois.
告诉我
Tell me.
克劳迪娅・毛里西奥是位好室友吗
Is Claudia Mauricio a good roommate?
是个好人吗
A good person?
我希望她也是这么看你的
I hope she feels the same about you.
谢尔碧  你不会相信路上的交通...
Oh, Shelby, you wouldn't believe the traffic on the...
你应该保持安静
You'll want to be quiet now.
克劳迪娅.
Claudia.
狱政局的某些机密资料
There are levels of clearance at the Department of Corrections.
是无法触及到的
That are simply not available.
即使我的那些无所不能的朋友也一样
Even for friends as connected as mine.
所以  仔细听好了
So, listen carefully.
如果对你的朋友的性命还有些许怜悯的话
If you even remotely value your friend's life.
你就用你的安全密码进入...
You're going to use your security code to access...
罪犯的转监记录
The records for prisoner transfers.
告诉我迈克尔・斯科菲尔德...
And tell me where they sent...
和林肯・布鲁斯被送到哪了
Michael Scofield and Lincoln Burrows.
我帮你拿吧
I can take that for you.
-谢谢  -不客气
-Thanks. -Sure.
你的包真不错
That's a great bag.
你从哪买的啊
Can I ask you where you got it?
是老板送我的礼物
It was a gift from my boss.
所以我也不知道  不好意思
So I don't really know, sorry.
没关系  谢谢了
Sure, thanks.
给你
There you go.
我从来都买不到合适的包
I can never find a good bag.
我是位老师  总要带很多书和卷子...
I'm a teacher, and I have books and grading materials and...
我也许该买一个...
I should probably go ahead and just invest...
像你那样的大包
In a wagon one of these days.
是的  所以我喜欢这个包
Yeah, that's why I love this bag.
有很多小口袋
It has so many pockets.
我能看一下吗
Do you mind if I take a look?
当然可以
Oh, no.
谢谢
Thanks.
感谢上帝  感谢上帝
Ah, thank God, thank God.
你没事吧  先生
You all right, mister?
是的  我那破车在几英里外抛锚了
Yeah, my damn truck blew a gasket a few miles back.
之后我一路步行过来的
I've been, uh, hoofing it ever since.
你要到哪去
Where you headed?
圣地亚哥
San Diego.
如果你想的话  我们可以载你一程
Hell, we can give you a ride, if you'd like.
你没事吧  伙计
Hey, what's wrong, man?
吃了墨西哥的烂食物了吗
Eat some bad Mexican?
差不多吧
Something like that.
跟昨天一样  很准时
Same as yesterday, right on schedule.
希望那东西还在她的包里
I hope to hell she's still got that thing in her purse.
塔克豪恩家
Tuxhorn residence.
你好  我是保安公司的
Hello, I'm from the alarm company.
我们从您家里接收到一些...
We've been receiving some, uh...
奇怪的信号
Strange signals from your property.
请您检查一下窗户好吗
We'd like you to check the windows, please.
确保所有的警报装置都运行正常
Make sure all the contacts are still active.
所有的窗户
All the windows?
是的  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
房子里的每个房间
Every room in the house.
好的  稍等
Okay, hold on.
她还带着包吗
Does she still have the bag?
是的
Yeah.
收到信号了
She's got it.
我正在接受房间里的所有信号  伙计
I'm picking up all kinds of gak from the house, man.
小玩意  也许是数码相机  mp3播放器
Small stuff, maybe a digital camera, an MP3 player.
还没有我们要找的东西
Nothing of the size of what we're looking for, though.
让她继续走
Keep her moving.
目前为止还不错  夫人
So far, so good, ma'am.
请您去下一个房间
Uh, please move on to the next room.
怎么样了
How we doing?
还没找到
Still don't got it.
如果卡在那里
If the card's in there.
就该藏在安全的地方  比如保险箱
It'd be in some kind of, a safe.
办公室
Office.
夫人  我们的系统显示...
Ma'am, our system is showing...
故障来自一间像是...
That the malfunction is coming from a room...
办公室或书房的房间
That's designated as, uh, an office or a den.
你说的是图书馆吗
You mean the library?
先生不喜欢我去那里
Mister doesn't like me going in there.
如果您没有设置好警报系统便下班回家的话...
Well, I think he'd like it even less if you went home...
我想他会更加不高兴  您认为呢
Without properly setting the alarm first, don't you think?
好吧  我去检查一下
All right, I'll check.
有信号了
We got something.
是卡吗
The card?
是的
Oh, yeah.
这么大的文件不可能是其他东西
File's so big it can't be anything else.
现在你要把她留在那里2分钟...
Now you just gotta keep her there...
保证完成数据传输
For two minute while it finishes the burn.
拖住她  我们需要2分钟
Stall her, we need two minutes.
夫人  我想我们找到问题所在了
Ma'am, I think we found the source of our problem.
如果你能...
If you could just stay...
在我们重启系统的过程中...
At that particular window and hold it closed...
把窗户关上  保持紧闭  问题就能解决了
While we reset the system, that should do it.
怎么样了  罗兰
Talk to me, Roland.
马上就好  马上  马上
It's almost there, almost, almost.
快  快  快
Come on, come on, come on.
快
Come on.
-完成了  -完成了
-Got it. -Got it.
好了  夫人  非常感谢您的帮助
All right, ma'am, thank you so much for your help.
我们现在要做的是...
All we need to do now, man, is just...
不  她又回去了
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, she's heading back inside.
-回去干嘛  -我不知道
-What for? -I don't know.
不
Oh, no.
不  没事
No, we're good.
她出来了
She's out.
站住
Hey, stop it!
在这等着
Wait here.
为了抓不到你  我不得不放慢脚步
I actually had to slow down not to catch you.
我想我的腿拉伤了
I think I pulled a groin.
不在包里
It's not in the bag.
-不在这里  -怎么会不在这里
-It's not here. -How could it not be in here?
那个接收器  不在包里  给我
The device, it's not here, give me it.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
美国联邦监狱  利文斯顿  德克萨斯州
US Federal Penitentiary, Livingston, Texas.
26  27  28
twenty-six, twenty-seven, twenty-eight.
请讲
Go ahead.
在布鲁斯和斯科菲尔德...
Before Burrows and Scofield...
被转移到阿灵顿之前
Were allegedlly transferred to Arlington.
有人替他们付了保释金
Someone posted their bail.
我要知道这个人是谁
I need to know who.
我查到是一个叫布鲁斯・班尼特的人
I'm showing a Bruce Bennett.
弗兰克・唐克雷蒂州长的前任助手
Former aid to Governor Frank Tancredi.
你们觉得那东西掉了吗
You think it fell out?
我们找遍了
We looked everywhere.
你们认为复制成功了吗
You think we got the thing copied?
我说了  在成功下载数据之前...
Like I said, I can't read the content...
我对内容也不得而知  但是...
Without downloading the device, but...
除非塔克豪恩录制了5万个小时的节目
Unless this Tuxhorn's got, like, a 50,000-hour Tivo.
否则的话  肯定是拷贝下来了
Then, yeah, I think we got it.
除非找到接收器  否则是否拷贝下来毫无意义
Doesn't matter if we got it if we can't find it.
接收器到底在哪
Where the hell is it?
还在房子里
It's still inside the house.
这就是女佣回去的原因
That's why the maid went back inside.
她一定发现了
She must have found it.
以为那是她老板的东西
Assumed it belonged to her boss.
所以她就送回去了
And then she left it behind.
你们猜如何  伙计们  游戏结束了
Well, then guess what, fellas, it's game over.
你知道我为了做那个东西...
You know how many months...
花费了多少时间吗  迈克尔
It took me to make that thing, Michael?
怎么  你以为我几秒钟就能再做一个出来吗
What, you just think I can whip up another one in a couple seconds?
丢了不是问题
Losing it is not the problem.
如果他们发现了  那才是问题
If they find it, that's the problem.
如果他们发现有人在找数据卡  我们就完了
If they find out someone was after that card, we're done.
完了是什么意思  你说什么呢
What do you mean, done?  What does that mean?
意思是说我们要回去蹲监狱了
Does that mean we're gonna go back to prison?
还是他们要干掉我们
Are they gonna kill us?
-到底是什么意思  -闭嘴
-What the hell does that mean? -Shut up!
意味着我们要进去把它取回来
Means we go in and get it.
如果我们有几天时间  就能找到解决的办法
If we had a few days, we'll figure out a way to pull this off.
但我猜我们没有那么多时间了
But I gather we don't have that kind of time.
是的  你猜的没错
Yeah, you gather right.
听着  如果你想要我们把接收器拿回来
Look, if you want us to get that device out of there.
你就得有所作为
You gotta throw us a bone.
给我们些额外的帮助
Give us some extra help.
你的要求  需要牵扯到其他的人
What you're asking for requires involving additional people.
那样我们的行动便会暴露
Which given the covert nature of this operation.
我做不到
I cannot do.
那你的要求便是可望不可及
Then you're asking for the impossible.
不  我的要求是努力  明白吗
No, what I'm asking for is competence, okay?
我不会把整个任务的成功与否...
I'm not the one who put the entire mission...
寄托在一个该死的女佣身上
In the hands of a damn maid.
听着  如果公司先找到锡拉的拷贝
Look, if the Company finds that copy of Scylla before we do.
那就完了  迈克尔  这是场竞赛
That's it, Michael, that's ball game.
他们会找出幕后的人
They're gonna find out who was behind it.
他们会干掉我们所有人
And they're going to ghost us.All of us.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
我没事
I'm fine.
听着  我并不是手握你的把柄...
Look, I didn't choose you to do this
逼着你做这个的
Because I had you in custody.
我是因为相信你的能力才让你做的
I chose you to do this.Because I believed you could pull it off.
是的  在过去的几个月里...
Yeah, well, a lot of people have believed in me...
许多人都信任我  赛尔夫特工
In the last few months, Agent Self.
他们都死了
Not all of them are alive today.
你到底能不能把接收器拿回来
Can you get me back the device or not?
好了  事情是这样的
All right, this is what we got.
在女佣离开的时候  她发现了接收器
The housekeeper saw the device as she was leaving the house.
然后她回到房子里15秒钟
Then she disappears back inside for 15 seconds.
那么我们就知道它的位置了
So, we know, wherever it is.
在门口附近
It's somewhere close to the door.
所以15秒钟
So, 15 seconds.
就是我们要争取到的时间
That's all we have to buy ourselves.
我不确定我们可以多么接近房子
Listen, I'm not sure how close we're gonna get to this house.
更别说潜入进去了
Let alone inside of it.
即便我们做到了
But let's say that we do.
房子配备的警报器会在任何窗户或门被...
The alarm they got installed in this house is triggered...
非法闯入后的1.2秒发出警报
1.2 seconds after broken contact in any door or window.
之后47个全副武装的...
Which would immediately send the private security guards...
私人保镖便会立即冲入房子
With their 47 guns rushing into the property.
30秒之后  保安公司...
And after 30 seconds, the alarm company...
就会派车过去
Will dispatch vehicles to the property.
三到四辆  视情况而定
Three to four, depending on availability.
证实有人非法闯入之后
After confirmation of a break-in.
他们会派更多的车来
They'll dispatch additional vehicles.
封闭房子的所有出入口
To seal off any and all exits from the property.
我不确定是否能行  迈克尔
I don't know about this, Michael.
现在很明显...
It's getting pretty clear...
他们为什么要找一帮罪犯来干这件事了
Why they hired a bunch of cons to do this job.
他们不仅想要置身度外
It's not because they wanted it off the books.
同时我们是毫无价值的
It's because we're expendable.
谁会在乎一帮罪犯被杀呢
Who's gonna care if a bunch of crooks wind up dead?
这是自杀行为
It's suicide.
我会继续查看可能有用的信息
I'm gonna keep looking and see what I can find.
奥德赛的片段
That quote from The Odyssey.
怎么了
What about it?
有一句不懂
I can't shake that line.
飞行是最好的办法
"All that avails is flight."
如果飞行是唯一的选择怎么办  林肯
What if flight is our only option, Linc?
如果我们的父亲在调查了...
What if our father after everything he discovered...
公司的一切之后  发现...
About the Company, what...
发现飞行是唯一的办法
What if that's what he finally realized?
知道吗  我记得关于爸爸最清楚的事...
You know, uh, the one thing I remember most...
就是他的背影
About Dad was the back of his head.
总是渐渐消失在大门口
Always walking out the front door.
总是在逃避着什么
Always running from something.
妈妈  我们  他自己
Mom, us, himself.
但是他唯一没有逃避的事情...
But the one thing he never ran away from...
就是公司一定得被搞垮的信念
Was his belief that the Company needed to be taken down.
我们现在有机会去完成这个信念
And we got an opportunity to do that.
那么这是我们的战斗  不是他们的
Then this is our fight, not theirs.
兄弟  这不是福克斯河监狱
Man, this ain't Fox River.
他们自己选择来这里
These guys chose to be here.
记住这点
Remember that.
他们自己的选择
They got a choice.
-快了  -准备好了吗
-Almost. -Ready?
走
Go.
快走  快走  快走
Let's go! Let's go! Go!
快  我们走
Come on, let's go.
声音从哪传来的
Where's it coming from?
街对面的
It's across the street.
走
Go.
是街对面的问题
Just something across the street.
我们派人过去检查了
We got a team checking it out now.
您可以回去了  先生
You can go back inside, sir.
他们一定是出城了
Must be out of town.
爸爸  没事吧
Daddy, is everything okay?
阿历克斯
Alex.
谢谢  吉姆
Thanks, Jim.
阿历克斯
Alex.
我们快走
Let's go.
走
Go!
别回头
Don't turn around.
除非你想在漫长的时间内...
Unless you'd like to experience a great deal of pain...
品尝漫长折磨的滋味
Over an even greater length of time.
你想要什么  随便拿
You-you know, just-just take whatever you want here.
我唯一想要的东西
The only thing I want from you.
布鲁斯  是一个简单的问题的答案
Bruce, is the answer to a simple question.
迈克尔・斯科菲尔德和林肯・布鲁斯在哪
Where are Michael Scofield and Lincoln Burrows?
我只是通过报纸知道的...
I only know what-what I read in the papers and...
三天前
Three days ago.
美国德克萨斯州利文斯顿的联邦监狱里...
There were 105 inmates in the supermax wing...
关押着105名囚犯
Of the U.S. penitentiary in Livingston, Texas.
那两兄弟本该被送到那里
Where the brothers were allegedly sent.
但那里还是只关押着105名囚犯
There are still 105 inmates there.
那段时间里没人被释放
And no one has been released during that time.
有人在导演一场骗局  布鲁斯
Someone is playing a shell game, Bruce.
我只是要找出幕后主使
I'm just trying to find out who.
我没有刑事司法管辖权
I have no criminal jurisdiction over.
我知道你把他们保释出来了
I know you bailed them out.
我知道你一直跟莎拉・唐克雷蒂有联系
I know you've been in contact with Sara Tancredi.
我发誓  我真的不知道他们在哪
I swear to you, I've no idea where they are.
我们走着瞧
I guess we'll see about that.
祝你好运  泰迪
Good luck, Teddy.
有你们这样的朋友  还需要好运气吗
Who needs luck when you got friends like you fellas, huh?
我把这份旧报纸带走  你们不介意吧
Hey, you mind if I take this old newspaper of yours with me?
没问题
No problem.
对你的朋友我很遗憾  朋友
Sorry to hear about your friend, dude.
没关系
It's all right.
他活的很有价值
He had a full life.
再见  泰迪
Later, Teddy.
开始吧
There you go.
Thirty-six.
Twenty-four.
拿到了吗
Did you get it?
确认一下是否有我们要的数据
Let's make sure we got what we wanted.
-林肯  -怎么
-Linc. -Yeah.
看好那东西
Don't let that thing out of your sight.
好的
All right.
我们胜利在望了
We're halfway there.
我们只是进到房子里  拿走东西
All we got to do is that little B and E.
然后我们就离开这里
And we're out of here.
提醒我  我还得去联系赛尔夫...
Reminds me, I need to get ahold of Self...
看我们时候能开始
See when we can get started.
这一切结束之后你有什么打算
So what are you gonna do when all this is over?
问的好
That's a good question.
兄弟  不管锡拉是什么
Brother, whatever this Scylla thing is.
它就是一堆乱码
It is a monster of a code.
不
No.
莎拉  我本想来问问你是否想跟我谈谈...
Sara, I was gonna come down here and ask if you...
发生在巴拿马的事情
Wanted to talk some more about what happened in Panama.
但我想我已经知道你的答案了
But, um, I think I already know what you're gonna say.
为什么
How's that?
因为你和我有些相似
Because you're a little like me.
你会说你没事  你能处理好
Because you're gonna say you're fine, that you can handle it.
所以...
So, um...
我就不问了
I'll just leave it at this.
我会陪你
I'm here.
无论什么时候你想说了  我都愿意听
Whenever you want to talk, I'm here.
谢谢
Thank you.
当我被抓的时候  唯一令我...
You know that the only thing that kept me alive.
坚持下去的信念就是能和你在一起
When I was being held was the thought of being with you.
我知道如果我有什么三长两短
But I also knew that if anything happened to me.
你就会责怪你自己
You were gonna blame yourself.
整个下半生都会沉浸在深深的自责当中
You would spend the rest of your life punishing yourself for it.
我想都不敢想
And, I can't bear the thought of that.
所以我们现在算是扯平了好吗
So can we make a deal right now that we're even.
往事一笔勾销  没有自责  没有责任
And just wipe the slate clean and no guilt and no responsibility?
如果我们还能在一起
If we're gonna be together.
我不希望你是出于为我负责的态度
I don't want it to be out of a sense of obligation.
即使我们应该这样
Or-or even that we should be.
因为我们经历了太多
Because of what we've been through.
我只想重新开始
I just want to start over.
重新开始
Start over.
好的
Okay.
这是否意味着我必须先离婚呢
But, does that mean I have to divorce my wife?
你和那个俄罗斯脱衣女郎还是合法夫妻
Because you're still married to a Russian stripper.
第一  我之前一直比较忙
Well, "A": I've been a little busy.
第二  我很确定她是捷克人
And "B": I'm pretty sure she was Czech.
迈克尔
Hey, Michael.
怎么了
What's wrong?
不管它是什么  反正不对
Whatever it is, it ain't it.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我记得你说过  我们拷贝了那张卡
I thought you said we copied the card.
是  没错
No, we did.
但根据加密编码...
But according to the encryption code...
我该怎么解释呢
Okay, how do I make this clear?
假如说锡拉是块披萨  我们得到的只是一片
If Scylla was like a pizza, all we got's a slice.
剩下的数据在哪
So where's the rest of the data?
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
我是说...
I mean...
我不知道我们为什么看不全
I mean, I don't know how we didn't see this coming.
应该是完全没有问题的
I mean, it-it makes perfect sense.
这就像是核武发射码
It's like the nuclear launch codes.
信息不可能只在一个人的手里
You don't give all that information to just one person.
那会分给多少人
How many do you give it to?
你父亲记录的奥德赛的那个片段说...
Okay, that quote your father held onto...
锡拉是一只六头妖怪
In The Odyssey Scylla is a six-headed monster.
想要通过就需要牺牲6位手下的生命
That requires a sacrifice of six soldiers in order to pass.
这么说锡拉不只是一张卡
So Scylla isn't one card.
是六张
It's six.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
我们如何能找到剩下的5张
How we gonna find five more of these things?
迈克尔  迈克尔
Michael! Michael!
我很忙
I'm busy.
我不在乎她现在怎么样了
I don't care what she looks like.
三勺水
Three tablespoons of water.
一勺蜂蜜
one of honey.
就这些
Nothing more.
即使她只知道哪怕是一点点的消息
If she knows something about anything that's going on.
我也要知道
I'm going to find it.
起床了  婊子
Rise and shine, bitch.
吃早餐
Breakfast.
迈克尔
Michael?
Hey, Michael!
你没事吧
You all right?
没事  我很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
这些保护措施让你不禁联想...
All this security makes you wonder...
公司到底在隐藏什么
What the Company's hiding.
弄清真相的唯一办法就是...
Only way to know for sure...
找到剩余的5张数据卡
Is to find those five other cards,
我们自己看
See for ourselves.
我们的时间够吗
Think we'll have enough time?
够
Yeah.
我们...
We'll, uh...
会没事的
We'll be fine.